宝石
狩猎
欢迎关注微博@ UUU字幕组 获取最新熟肉信息!
出品
UUU字幕组
翻译
饼干一枚/ 右翼部鸣明
校对
牙牙/ Husky/ Linn
特效
presisco
压制
时间轴 SG 文本处理 谷子 yoyo
俺们到啦!~
We're here!
果然只有亲自来北方才能体会到这种美啊
The great north is so beautiful in person.
等下 等下 呆在那别动
Wait, wait, stay right there!
好啦 笑一个
All right, smile!
好 现在做出你们
Okay, now one where it looks like
在找怪物的样子
you're looking for a monster!
不错 现在做出像是在讲笑话的样子
Okay, now one like you made a joke!
行 那么现在 做出那个笑话乍一听不那么好笑
Okay, now, do one where the joke's not that funny,
但是要想一会才get到笑点的样子
but it's more like a joke that makes you think.
好啦 我认为差不多也照够了吧
Okay, I think that's enough photography.
但这可是康妮小天使的第一次任务啊
But it's Connie's first mission!
她的父母让我多拍点照片回来
Her parents asked me to take lots of pictures.
非常感谢您能够让我
Thank you so much for letting me
参与这个任务 珍珠
come on this mission, Pearl.
很荣幸能和您一起工作
It's such an honor to work alongside you.
哦 康妮 你的剑术水平
Well, Connie, your sword-fighting skills
已经远远超过我所期望的了
have far exceeded my expectations.
再加上我小心的教导
And, with my careful supervision, of course,
我当然可以相信你能够轻松搞定
I'm confident that you can handle
这样一个简单的宝石修复任务
a simple gem-recovery mission like this.
太感谢您了
Thank you so much!
我保证我绝对不会让您失望! 老师!
I promise I won't let you down, ma'am!
康妮第一次任务唔嗷嗷嗷嗷嗷嗷
Connie's first mission!
复述一遍任务目标 康妮
Recap the mission for us, Connie.
石榴感觉到了一些堕转的宝石在这森林里浪得很嗨
Garnet sensed some corrupted gem activity in these woods.
而我们的任务就是找到它们的位置
It is our job to locate it,
解决掉它们并用泡泡收容
destabilize its form and bubble it.
非常不错
Very good.
你的人类身体无法
Now, your human bodies aren't designed
适应严寒
to last in this cold,
所以我们必须要特别小心
so we'll have to be extra careful.
那没问题 我的背包里已经装满了
That's okay. I've got this backpack filled
能让我们在野外多活一会儿的东西
with everything we need to survive in the wilderness.
我还带来三国杀以免我们无聊
And I brought board games in case we get bored.
啊 可以 很不错
Ah, yes. Very good.
所以 我们该怎么知道这些损坏了的宝石在附近?
So, how will we know if this corrupted gem is nearby?
就是这么知道的 它来了
That's how! Here it comes!
记住 你们要一起战斗
Remember, you work together!
准备好了吗 康妮 准备好了 史蒂文
Ready, Connie? Ready, Steven!
居然有两只
Two of them?!
史蒂文 泡泡辅助
Steven, bubble!
泡泡防护罩
Bubble power!
它们...跑路了
They...ran away?
本来不应该有两只才对
There weren't supposed to be two.
噢 噢--我有个主意
Oh, oh--I have an idea!
我们可以分头行动
We could split up!
你去追那一只 珍珠
You can go after one of them, Pearl,
我和史蒂文去追另一只
and Steven and I will go after the other one.
康妮 你是我的学生
Connie, you are my pupil,
所以我清楚你的战斗技术很优秀
so I know your combat skills are excellent.
但是我担心这样太冒险了
But I'm afraid this is too risky.
你们之前还没有参加过真正的战斗
You've never been in a real fight before.
这个 也不完全对
Well, that's not true.
康妮打败过那些宝石实验体
Connie defeated those gem experiments at the hospital.
但--
But--
还有你看
And look!
我带了这些对讲机
I brought these walkie-talkies
如果出现意外 我们可以互相联系
so we can talk to each other in case something happens!
可--
But--
我已经在之前已经读了这本书至少20次
And I've read this book front to back, at least 20 times!
如何求生
逃过大自然的惩罚
那好吧
Well, all right.
但是一会儿一旦找到了怪物 就要立刻联系我
But as soon as you find the monster, contact me immediately.
我不想你们独自与那玩意战斗
I don't want you fighting this thing alone.
再问一次 你们要找到什么
One more time, what are you looking for?
怪兽
A monster.
找到它后你们会做什么
What do you do when you find it?
联系你
Call you.
谁是你们最喜欢的宝石
And who's your favorite gem?
珍珠啦啦啦啦
Pearl!
哎呀 谢谢啦
Why, thank you!
那么 注意安全
Now, be safe!
是的 长官
Yes, ma'am!
我们现在要做的就是跟着这些脚印
All we have to do is follow these tracks.
不错 这些都是新鲜的
Yeah. These are fresh.
我们跟踪它直到它停下来休息为止
We trail it until it stops to rest.
哇 康妮 你简直是贝爷第二
Wow, Connie, you're a wilderness expert.
哦 我喜欢事先准备好一切
Well, I like to be prepared.
当文明崩溃 世界终结之时
When civilization collapses and this world ends,
我需要准备好创造一个新的世界
I need to be ready to build the new one.
是啊 我猜如果地球被母星侵略的话
Yeah, I guess if homeworld invades Earth,
事态对人类来说会非常失控
things could get pretty crazy for humanity.
别管宝石了
Forget gems.
人类已经迎来了他们自己造成的末日
Humans are already starting their own demise!
石油危机啊 史蒂文
Peak oil, Steven!
吾等该如何解决这祸灾
How do we handle terminal decline
而不需要备用能源
without alternate energy sources?!
你俩在做什么
How are you two doing?
你们饿了吗
Are you hungry?
别忘了 你们人类是需要吃东西的
Remember, you humans need to eat!
是的 长官
Yes, ma'am!
还好我装备了好多的生存'燃料'
Luckily, I packed plenty of survival fuel.
是时候补充蛋白质了!
Time to get our protein on!
还好这里刚下了雪
Good thing this snow is here--
这样更方便我们追踪怪兽
it makes following tracks a lot easier.
当然
I'll say!
所以这些堕转的宝石就像野生动物
So, these corrupted gems are like wild animals.
只有一些战斗和逃跑的条件反射
Just a bundle of fight or flight reflexes
以及生存本能
and survival instincts.
唔嗯 他们现在是这样 但是之前的他们不是
Well, they're like that now, but before they were different.
他们曾经是正常的宝石人 就像珍珠 紫晶和石榴一样
They used to be normal gems like Pearl, Amethyst, and Garnet.
他们也拥有思想和感觉 朋友......
They had thoughts and feelings, friends...
我不知道堕转对它们来说是怎么样的
I don't really know how the corruption works.
大概像是生病了一样
It's like they're sick.
她们不记得自己以前是谁
They don't remember who they used to be.
也许她们连自己原来
Maybe they don't even know
长什么样都忘记了
how to look like themselves anymore.
你还好吧
You okay?
嗯 我没事
Yeah, I'm good.
噢 我知道怎样可以让我换个心情了
Oh, I know what'll cheer me up!
史蒂文 康妮
Steven, Connie?
我完全失去这只怪兽的踪迹了
I'm not having any luck finding this monster.
也许我们应该回到神庙重新编队
We might have to return to the temple and regroup.
不 不用 我们可以搞定的
No, no! We can handle it!
现在进展非常顺利
We're making great progress.
我们完全可以自己解决
We can definitely take care of this ourselves!
嘛 好吧 你听起来挺自信的
Oh, well, you sound very confident.
那就继续任务吧 还有记住了 康妮
Carry on then, and remember, Connie...
打开步伐 压低重心 我都记得的 老师
Stance wide, body lowered. I've got it, ma'am.
平衡即是关键
♪ Balance is the key ♪
-需要帮忙吗-是的 谢谢
Need some help there? Yes, please.
哇 看看这些脚印
Whoa. Look at the tracks.
哇
Whoa.
看这一团乱七八糟的痕迹
Now, this is a mess.
其中的一些看起来像人的脚印
Some of these prints look humanoid.
珍珠来过这里吗
Could pearl have been here?
但是珍珠往另一个方向走了
But Pearl went the other direction.
怪兽的...人的...怪兽的
Monster...humanoid...monster.
这意味着什么呢
What could this mean?
我们应该搭建一个躲避暴风雪的庇护所
We should probably take shelter from this blizzard.
但是首先 要先收集一些松针
But first, let's grab some of these pine needles.
我们可以用它来泡一些富含维C的茶
We can brew a vitamin-C-rich tea with them
这样我们就不会得败血病
so we don't get scurvy.
就像海盗一样
Like a pirate.
茶泡好了
The tea's ready!
来 尝一下
Here, try it!
谢谢
Thanks!
味道如何
How is it?
很
It's...
很难喝
It's bad.
当然了
Well, yeah.
好不好喝不重要
It's not about tasting good, Steven,
重要的是在大自然的惩罚下生存下来
it's about surviving the punishment of nature.
所以说 为什么那里会有人形的脚印
So, why were there humanoid tracks out there?
那不是我们的 也不是珍珠的
They weren't ours, and they weren't Pearl's.
更不可能是怪兽的
It couldn't have been the monster.
除非是一个装扮成怪兽的人
Unless it's just some guy in a monster suit.
但那种事只在动画片里发生
But that kind of thing only happens in cartoons,
而且通常是因财产纠纷引发的
usually over a property dispute.
也许就是一个装扮成怪兽的人呢
Maybe it is a guy in a monster costume.
你也这么认为?
You think so?
当然不是字面上的意思了 傻瓜
I don't mean literally, silly.
我的意思是也许在那怪兽的外表之下
What I mean is there might be a conscious gem
还有一个神志清醒的宝石人
still inside there somewhere.
这可能吗
Is that possible?
也许它还在怪兽与原型之间
What if the monster is turning back and forth
不断转换
into its original form.
如果真是那样 也许它还没有像我们认为的那样彻底堕转
If it is, it might not be as corrupted as we think.
我们可能还有机会拯救它
There might still be a chance to save it.
怎么救
How?
我不能治愈堕转的宝石人--
I can't heal gems that are corrupted--
起码不能治愈完全堕转的
at least not all the way.
但是如果它没有完全堕转...
But if it's half-corrupted...
这边
This way!
嘘
Shh!
它看起来很害怕 是在害怕我们吗
It seems scared. Is it running from us?
如果它是在害怕...它自己呢
What if it's running...from itself?
嘘 小声点
Shh!\ Keep your voice down!
你们好啊
Hello, you two!
那里进展如何
How's it going?
天气真的变得越来越恶劣了
This weather has really taken a turn for the worse,
我可不想为
and I would hate to be responsible
你们陷入危险负责
for putting you two in danger.
确保你们穿得--
Make sure you bundle up with--
-史蒂文 快关掉-我正在关呢
Steven! Turn it off! I'm trying!
噢 还有 别忘了 如果你们找到了怪兽
Oh! And, remember, if you find the monster,
千万不要发出任何惊天动地的声音
don't make any loud, startling noises.
-喂 在吗-这天杀的手套怎么这么滑
Hello?! Anyone there?! Stupid, slipper mittens.
你们不回答 我就继续说啦
I'm just going to keep talking until somebody answers.
史蒂文
Steven!
等下 让我先试试与它交流
Wait. Let me try talking to it.
嘿 你好吗
Hey. How's it going?
呃 你能听懂我吗
Um, can you hear me?
你还清醒吗
Are you in there somewhere?
你可以控制住的
You can control this.
快想起你以前是谁
Remember who you used to be.
史蒂文 我不觉得有用
Steven, I don't think it's working.
史蒂文
Steven!
嘿 看这儿
Hey! Over here!
康妮 你在干什么
Connie, what are you doing?!
我...
I...
我不知道
I don't know.
我还没有准备好
I...wasn't prepared for this.
史蒂文 康妮
Steven, Connie?!
你们不说话是因为我问的"你最喜欢的宝石"吗
Is this because of the "favorite gem"thing?
哈 那只是开玩笑而已啦
Heh, that was just a joke!
千万别告诉石榴
Don't tell garnet.
康妮
Connie!
珍珠 我们找到怪兽了
Pearl, we found the monster!
-啥-我们需要支援
What?! We need your help!
我马上过来 康妮
I'll be right there, Connie!
那是谁
Who's that?!
防-防-防-防-防-防御
B-B-B-B-B-B-Bubble!
铁石英 那些脚印
Jasper. Those footprints.
那些怪物是在害怕她
The monsters were running from her.
康妮 怪兽在--
Connie, where's the--
铁石英
Jasper!
嘿 玫瑰 看我抓到了什么
Hey, Rose, look what I got.
你俩没事吧
Are you two okay?
嗯 我们没事
Yeah, we're fine.
噢 谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness.
真是一场灾难
What a disaster.
要是当初我知道铁石英也在这儿
I never would have let you come on this mission
就不会让你参与这次任务
if I knew Jasper would be here.
-对不起-啊?
I'm sorry. What?
我以为我已经做好了战斗的准备 但其实我没有
I thought I'd be ready to fight, but I wasn't.
我失败了
I failed.
我本来就没让你战斗
You weren't supposed to fight.
我只让你联系我 而你也这么做了
You were supposed to call me, and you did.
你完全成功了
This was a total success.
康妮的首次任务
Connie's first mission!
来张合照
Group picture.
史蒂文
Steven!
噢 又要拍照
Oh. Another picture?
当你要拍了就告--
Tell me when you--
拍好了
Eh, got it.
噢 不
Oh, no.
你的爸妈会看见这个吗
Are your parents going to see this?
我的爸妈会看我所有的照片
My parents see all of my photos, ma'am.